transperth.wa.gov.au 2019-06-10

# Transperth Home

**Last Updated: 29/03/2018**

**Introduction**

This Privacy Statement explains how Transperth, part of the WA State Government’s Public Transport Authority (“us” or “we”), collects, uses and discloses your personal information.

This Privacy Statement may change periodically, so please check back from time to time. For your information, the date of the last update to this Privacy Statement is stated at the top of this statement.

**The personal information we collect and how it is collected**

When you access this website, our internet service provider makes a record of your visit and logs the following information for statistical purposes:

  * Your server address;
  * Your top level domain name (for example .com, .gov, .au, .uk etc);
  * The date and time of your visit to the site;
  * The pages you accessed and documents downloaded;
  * The previous site you have visited; and
  * The type of browser you are using.

This information about your use is only analysed on a bulk basis for broad demographic content. Individual use is not analysed.

In certain areas of the Transperth’s website, we may ask you to provide your name, gender, date of birth and contact details by registering for the website or participating in surveys.

If you complete and application form or if you use the Transperth’s website to complete an online application form or booking we will collect any personal information you provide on that form which may include your name, date of birth, gender, marital status, address, email and telephone number. We will only collect the information contained in that online application form if you submit the form to us. If you log out of the website or cancel the application prior to submitting the form, the information you had entered will be automatically deleted.

Depending on the application made we may also collect credit card or debit account details in order to provide you with our goods or services.

If you use Transperth’s online feedback form then we will collect your name, email address and Smartrider number.

We will record your e-mail address if you send us a message.

If you have purchased or been issued with a Smartrider card we will collect information relating to your use of public transport and travel concession entitlement details.

If you use Smartparker we will collect information relating to your use of public transport parking facilities and motor vehicle registration details.

If you use the Transperth mobile application we will collect information as to your activity, location, telephone number and IP address.

**How we use your personal information**

We may use your personal information to administer our services to you, manage our relationship with you, improve our services and send you newsletters or other PTA related commuter information.

We will not use or disclose personal information, including information collected using cookies, other than for a purpose made known to you, a purpose you would reasonably expect, a purpose required, authorised or permitted by or under any law, or a purpose otherwise authorised by you.

**Sharing of your personal information**

We may provide personal information to third parties including contractors who provide certain services related to the services of PTA. These services include but are not limited to information technology support, electronic funds transfer services, credit card account processing and related services, call centre support and production of cards.

We may also share personal information with related PTA services including Transwa.

**Use of cookies**

Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to an individual's hard drive for record keeping purposes. The cookie assigns you an ID which allows us to recognise you when you return to the website. We use "cookies" to deliver content specific to your interests so users do not have to register each time they use the website.

**Security**

Personal information is securely stored by us and by third parties on our behalf. Fire walls and virus protection software are in place to protect our systems and data.

All personal information that is no longer required to be retained is destroyed or de-identified.

**Contact Information**

If you have an enquiry or complaint in relation to this Privacy Statement please contact enquiries@transperth.wa.gov.au

## Terms of use - Transperth website and applications

Your use of the Transperth website or applications constitutes your agreement to these terms of use.

**No unlawful or prohibited use**

You may not use the Transperth website or applications for any purpose that is unlawful or prohibited by these terms, in any manner which could damage, disable, overburden, or impair, or interfere with any other party's use and enjoyment of, the Transperth website or applications. You may not obtain or attempt to obtain any materials or information through any means not intentionally made available or provided for through the Transperth website or applications.

**Use of communication services**

The Transperth website or applications may contain bulletin board services, chat areas, news groups, forums, communities, personal web pages, calendars, and/or other message or communication facilities designed to enable you to communicate with the public at large or with a group ("Communication Services"), you agree to use the Communication Services only to post, send and receive messages and material that are proper and related to the particular Communication Service. By way of example, and not as a limitation, you agree that when using a Communication Service, you will not:

Defame, abuse, harass, stalk, threaten or otherwise violate the legal rights (such as rights of privacy and publicity) of others.

Publish, post, upload, distribute or disseminate any inappropriate, profane, defamatory, infringing, obscene, indecent or unlawful topic, name, material or information.

Upload files that contain software or other material protected by intellectual property laws (or by rights of privacy of publicity) unless you own or control the rights thereto or have received all necessary consents.

Upload files that contain viruses, corrupted files, or any other similar software or programs that may damage the operation of another's computer.

Advertise or offer to sell or buy any goods or services for any business purpose, unless such Communication Service specifically allows such messages.

Conduct or forward surveys, contests, pyramid schemes or chain letters.

Download any file posted by another user of a Communication Service that you know, or reasonably should know, cannot be legally distributed in such manner.

Falsify or delete any author attributions, legal or other proper notices or proprietary designations or labels of the origin or source of software or other material contained in a file that is uploaded.

Restrict or inhibit any other user from using and enjoying the Communication Services.

Violate any code of conduct or other guidelines which may be applicable for any particular Communication Service.

Harvest or otherwise collect information about others, including e-mail addresses, without their consent.

Violate any applicable laws or regulations.

Transperth has no obligation to monitor the Communication Services. However Transperth reserves the right to review materials posted to a Communication Service and to remove any materials in its sole discretion. Transperth reserves the right to terminate your access to any or all of the Communication Services at any time without notice for any reason whatsoever.

Transperth reserves the right at all times to disclose any information as necessary to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, or to edit, refuse to post or to remove any information or materials, in whole or in part, in Transperth’s sole discretion.

Materials uploaded to a Communication Service may be subject to posted limitations on usage, reproduction and/or dissemination. You are responsible for adhering to such limitations if you download the materials.

**Materials provided to Transperth**

Transperth does not claim ownership of the materials you provide to Transperth (including feedback and suggestions) or post, upload, input or submit to Transperth’s website, applications or its associated services ("Submissions"). However, by posting, uploading, inputting, providing or submitting your Submission you are granting Transperth, its contractors, subcontractors and agents permission to use your Submission in connection with the operation of their Internet businesses including, without limitation, the rights to: copy, distribute, transmit, publicly display, publicly perform, reproduce, edit, translate and reformat your Submission; and to publish your name in connection with your Submission.

No compensation will be paid with respect to the use of your Submission. Transperth is under no obligation to post or use any Submission you may provide and may remove any Submission at any time in its sole discretion.

By posting, uploading, inputting, providing or submitting your Submission you warrant and represent that you own or otherwise control all of the rights to your Submission as described in this section including, without limitation, all the rights necessary for you to provide, post, upload, input or submit the Submissions.

**Termination/access restriction**

Transperth reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to terminate your access to the Transperth website or its applications at any time, without notice.

**Liability**

To the extent permitted by law, neither Transperth, PTA nor the State of Western Australia shall be liable to any person or entity for any loss or damage which may arise from the use of any content on the Transperth website or its applications.

## Social Media Public Policy (House Rules)

**Policy Overview**

Transperth recognises social media channels as convenient for both passengers and non-passengers to obtain news, promotions, and other information directly relevant to transport in WA.

Official Public House Rules have been developed for all members of the public who comment on, or interact with, any of the Transperth online properties. They are outlined here to ensure high quality participation, in a manner that does not infringe the rights of, or restrict the use and enjoyment of the channel, by any other person.

**House Rules**

While Transperth supports open-dialogue, when interacting with our online media, you agree to:

  * Participate with the intention of adding value to, or benefitting the experience of, using public transport. If it helps you and other users of Transperth to navigate the service; if it helps our employees or partners do their jobs and solve problems; if it contributes directly or indirectly to improving Transperth’s services; if it builds a sense of community, then it is adding value
  * Aim to be fair, truthful and accurate
  * Take issue with the opinion, not the person
  * Be respective of other people's reputations
  * Be gentle when pointing out someone else's error or misinterpretation
  * Don't spam others - it makes it hard to have a real conversation
  * Remember that social updates from Transperth are written by Transperth staff

**Things to avoid**

  * Don’t use language containing expletives or hate speech
  * Avoid writing anything racist, discriminatory, offensive, abusive, threatening, harassing, false, misleading, defamatory, or unlawful
  * Don't use copyrighted material without the owner's permission
  * Don't use Transperth online properties for self-promotion or commercial gain

Transperth has the right to remove any post seen as breaking the House Rules, as well as the right to report or block any user from which we receive a pattern of rule-breaking activity.

**Comment moderation**

All Transperth online properties are actively monitored during normal business hours (see individual account properties for details). However, we do not have the capacity to monitor our accounts 24 hours per day, nor respond to each individual user. We will join the conversation where reasonable, when capacity allows.

Our team reads all direct messages and public online commentary, and any recurring themes or helpful feedback are passed to the relevant people internally.

If journey-specific or live service information is required, users are instructed to visit the Transperth website at www.transperth.wa.gov.au.

For urgent enquiries call the Transperth InfoLine on 13 62 13.

**Following**

If you follow us on an online platform we will not automatically follow you back. However, being followed by Transperth does not imply endorsement of any kind.

**Content sharing**

All content produced by Transperth on online properties, is protected by copyright. However, you are encouraged to share our content provided that you credit us as the source (by including our official social media handle for the platform you are sharing on, see individual channels for details) and do not change the sense or misrepresent us.

**For a formal response**

Transperth social media channels are informal. If you'd like a formal response from us, please complete the feedback form on our website.
